Guide to the Alan Rabinowitz papers, 1960-2017.
Rabinowitz, Alan papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alan Rabinowitz papers, 1960-2017.
6708
Alan Rabinowitz,1884-1973
2 cubic ft.
Printed Materials, Printed Materials, Publications, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports and documents relating to his work in planning, housing, urban renewal, municipal finance and urban economics, which integrate the worlds of public planning, public finance, and private development.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
City planner. Member Lambda Alpha International, New York Chapter (1950s) and Puget Sound Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports and documents relating to his work in planning, housing, urban renewal, municipal finance and urban economics, which integrate the worlds of public planning, public finance, and private development.
Report on "Non-planning and Redevelopment in Boston," 1972; two bound volumes of reports on planning and land development in Florida, Missouri, California, and Chicago written while on the staff of Arthur D. Little, Inc., Cambridge, MA. and other Arthur D. Little reports, 1960-1963; bound volume: "Industrial Zoning in Seattle, 1974;" bound volume, "Management of Tourism in Massachusetts," 1965. Also, M.I.T. dissertation, "Municipal Debt/Intergovernmental Fiscal Relations," 1969; "An Alternate Plan for Cooper Square," 1961; various Lambda Alpha publications; and selective bibliography and work history, 2006.
Materials about the Cambridge Institute, its New City Project, and its related Center for Community Economic Development.
Additional books, consulting reports and organizational materials, writings on historical underpinnings of city and regional planning, readings on progressive planning, professional papers and studies on urban planning/economics topics.
Research reports used for The Real Estate Gamble and Municipal Data Projection Project reports.
"Clara's Town: A Passion Play in the Years 1908-1910," an account by Alan Rabinowitz, with diary entries, relating to his mother Clara Greenhut. "Alan's Iconography of New York," 1914: an illustrated tour of places where members of their families (Rabinowitz and Wolf) have lived in Manhattan; places that are featured in the biography of Aaron Rabinowitz; including his connection to Fred F. French; and other connections to French's family and his companies.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rabinowitz, Alan, 1884-1973; Thabit, Walter, 1921-2005; Greenhut, Clara.; Rabinowitz family.; Wolf family.; French, Fred F. (Fred Fillmore), 1883-1936; Arthur D. Little, Inc.; Cambridge Institute (Cambridge, Mass.); Center for Community Economic Development.; Lambda Alpha International.; Planners for Equal Opportunity.
Subjects:
City planning--Massachusetts--Boston.; City planning--Florida.; City planning--Missouri--Kansas City.; City planning--California.; City planning--New York (N.Y.); City planning--Illinois--Chicago.; City planning--Washington--Seattle.; Zoning--Washington--Seattle.; Tourism--Massachusetts.; City planners.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collections: Walter Thabit papers, #4215 http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMM04215.
NOTES
Part of the Lambda Alpha Literary Archives.
CONTAINER LIST
- Non-Planning & Re-development in Boston, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A. Rabinowitz selected bibliography, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lambda Alpha International Membership directory, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Municipal Debt - Intergovernmental Fiscal Relations, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Arthur D. Little, Inc. (ADL): surveys of the Florida economy, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
- ADL reports, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Industrial Zoning in Seattle, 1964 (Box 1)
- USC (Urban Survey Corporation): Measurement of Tourism in Massachusetts, 1965 (Box 1)
- Cambridge Institute and New City Project, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Center for Community Development (CCED): the community context of economic conversion, Barry Stein, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cambridge Institute, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Planners for Equal Opportunity (PEO), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- New York State Urban Development Corp., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Management Associations, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Real Estate Investment Climate 1929-1975, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Professional papers and studies on urban planning/economics topics, 1957-1971 (Box 1)
- Walter Thabit and Cooper's Square Renovations, 1963 (Box 1)
- A. R. on Walter Thabit and Cooper's Square, 2007 (Box 1)
- Development of the Real Estate Investment Industry - 1925-1975, 1978 (Box 2)
- Professional papers and studies, 1971-1979 (Box 2)
- Professional papers and studies, 1980-1985 (Box 2)
- Development of the Real Estate Investment Industry - 1925-1975, 1978 (Box 2)
- Other papers on urban finance and economics, 1970-1986 (Box 2)
- Municipal Data Projection Project, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Revised populations of SMSAs (Standard Metropolitan Statistical Areas) 1920-1960, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fiscal data for school & special districts, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Municipal Analyst's Almanac, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Relative Growth of Cities in Metropolitan Areas since 1930, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Report on the Pilot Project, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Revenues, Expenditures, Debts 1955-1964, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Municipal Data Projection Project, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Non-Planning & Re-development in Boston c.2, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Markets for New Construction 1980-87-95, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Goodmoney Collective, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A.C.T.I.O.N., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Regional Plan Association (RPA) reports, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Report to W. M. K. Transit Mix, Inc., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Military housing, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Land development in Newton, Mass., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Municipal Debt/Intergovernmental Fiscal Relations, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- American City Corporation, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Alyeska Project (Alaska), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- King County Property Taxes and the Port of Seattle, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Economic Aspects of Redevelopment in Kakaako (Hawaii), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- The State of the Region: Vol. 1, No. 1 - Vol. 2, No. 8, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Winnick, Louis, et al: Philanthropy's Adaptation to the Urban Crisis (unpublished manuscript), 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Lambda Alpha membership lists, 1969, 1971, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- An Alternate Plan for Cooper Square, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Packet III: Writings on historical underpinnings of city and regional planning, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
- Packet IV: Readings on progressive planning, 1983 (Box 4)
- Centennial biography of Aaron Rabinowitz - 1884-1984, by Alan Rabinowitz, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Centennial history of Fred French - 1883-1983, by Alan Rabinowitz, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 1942 Bishop's Service confidential report on the Fred F. French Investing Co. Inc., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "So long, Avalon - or - Farewell, F-1," by Stephen Thompson, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "Background note," by Alan Rabinowitz, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Spear and Company Bulletin: A Journal for Realty Owners, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Financial History, 1928-1980, of the Fred F. French Investing Company," compiled and analyzed by Alan Rabinowitz, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Annual financial reports of the FFF Investing Co., 1928-1980 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
- Microfilm of 40-50 important documents, 1920s-1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- The French Plan, 11th edition, September 1929 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Articles about FFF and various enterprises, 1924-1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Tudor City historic district, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Financial history of Tudor City, New York, 1930-1968, by Alan Rabinowitz, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Tudor City court case 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Properties built and managed by FFF companies, 1923-1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- The paradox of the American metropolis, by Alan Rabinowitz, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 17)